don't take AP Computer Science it rots
your brain it teaches ancient techniques
like object-oriented classes and
inheritance which the creators of
object-oriented programming have
disavowed and said I quote the single
worst thing that was created in object
Orient programming was inheritance I
regret it I wish I could take it
back why on Earth would you do AP
computer science that teaches you these
broken principles and refuses even
though they take money hand over fist
from educational institutions and
students like you
constantly and makes revisions every
year and refuses to update their core
computer science principles to represent
modern programming with composition and
embedded structs and things that goang
will teach you that Java never will if
College boards watch this I hope they do
let me just show you how stupid College
Board is this happened in 2016 in 2016 I
had somebody taking AP Computer Science
come to me and say Mr Rob I missed a I
missed a question on the AP Computer
Science test can you believe
it and they had answered that lists
indexes start with zero and they got it
wrong because the stupid version of java
that they have that's not even Java okay
it's not even Java Java and with index
indexes start at zero the only languages
that start with one are Lua which is
totally stupid I think
Ada what's another one I can't think of
another one so College Board is teaching
AP Computer Science and they they they
have this thing that looks like Java but
they won't own it and say it's actually
Java they say it's derived from java and
then what do they do they do dumb
like change the initial index to one
because that will make more sense to
people but then as soon as they code in
other language and including Java they
will get it wrong because they will do a
zero it's such a stupid simple thing but
I really want you to understand this
something this is dumb this is so stupid
and this this demonstrates a fundamental
misunderstanding of basic modern
computer science principles I have never
felt more strongly by something than I
ever AP Computer Science needs to die in
its current form I spoke at length with
the creator of the original computer
science test which I shall not name in
an email going back and forth deciding
when I started my own company to teach
coding to people whether I should base
it on AP Computer Science I turned down
several highly paid jobs building
computer science AP Computer Science
programs for different private schools
because I said no I refuse to teach it
it's absolutely stupid it's totally the
stupidest thing it's made by people who
don't know how to code at all and yet
these are the people that our children
are learning from in the AP Computer
Science Program which continues to
happily take checks from companies who
have to take and also you want to know
what the Creator there's I'll I'll write
to you about the list the cs50 creators
the people at Harvard there's a question
out there should I still take computer
science 101 or whatever the hell be even
though I I got AP credit you know what
the answer was there and at other
universities yes because we have found
that most people who took AP Computer
Science were not properly prepared for
this course therefore you should take
the course anyway kaching cuz Academia
there is not anything on this
right now in terms of professionalism
that will get under my skin more than
this people who take money from
well-meaning
computer teachers and from well-meaning
students and they screw them up and then
these people go into the workforce and
they don't have an idea how to do modern
programming they've never heard of the
difference between inheritance versus
composition because they don't even talk
about it in the
materials all right that's it if you do
if you want more opinions about this if
you want to come talk to me about what
you should do instead let me know in
fact because of this I started my own
company I took my own retirement money
out at a 40% loss to start a computer
science education school and at the time
and it's all available for free now am I
grifting for myself kind of because I
think you and you don't even have to
come to me you can go someplace else
just don't do college board don't give
them their time don't give them their
money you're not going to learn anything
good from there you would learn more
learning how to write an application in
Java for your own usage like making a
mobile app which is Java and that kind
of thing cin than you ever would going
into one of these stupid ass AP Computer
Science classes just don't do it don't
I'm telling you if you do it you're
going to be wasting your time you're
going to be wasting your time there's so
many better things to do because this
thing has made me so angry the reason
I'm writing it right now is because I
have started to write learned Code War a
code Wizard's First spell book so that I
can teach the fundamentals of AP
Computer Science before these kids get
into AB Computer Science because if then
if they actually their parents make them
take AP Computer Science so they can be
a coder someday they can maybe have a
book that will help them use composition
and all those wonderful things before
they ever go to AB Computer Science and
then they can tell the teacher how wrong
they are about everything and get kicked
out of the class and be better off for
it all right I'm done I'm done